Justin Bishay

Online Portfolio: https://justinbishay.wixsite.com/portfolio

1146 Leilipoa Way • Honolulu, HI 96825 • Phone: (808) 782-7438 • E-Mail: jkbishay.egypt@gmail.com

Profile

Undergraduate computer science student experienced with programming in C, C#, HTML, and Java. Full-time student with above average grades and passionate about coding. Work on various Augmented and Virtual Reality projects both professionally and personally. Developed a 2D arcade-style shooter video in my spare time. Developed a 2D puzzle platformer game as part of a large collaborative group project.

Experience

Laboratory for Advanced Visualization and Applications

January 2018 – present

- Trained to install, troubleshoot, and manage Data Visualization software and hardware known as CyberCANOE
- Work on augmented and virtual reality projects involving data visualization

PACXA - Intern

June 2014, August 2014

- · Installed and setup modified iPads in hotel rooms at the Sheraton Waikiki and Royal Hawaiian hotels
- Worked with a team 7-10 technicians to troubleshoot and resolve issues

Ohana Komputer - Curriculum Editor (Google Drive)

June 2017 – September 2017

- Used Google Docs to edit and update Microsoft Office curriculum to be taught with Google Drive applications
- Updated lesson plans for Google Docs, Google Sheets, and Google Slides
- · Formatted the layout of documents in Google Docs

eSports - Assistant Tournament Organizer & Streamer

March 2017 - present

- Voluntarily assist in running double-elimination tournament brackets for competitive Super Smash Bros. Wii U
- Help to maintain and edit Twitch live stream of tournament matches throughout the tournament with XSplit
- Set up and take apart streaming equipment and tournament match stations
- · Have also casted/commentated tournament matches for two years

Mid-Pacific Institute Athletic - Coach

August 2015 - present

- · Assistant coach for the cross-country and track and field teams
- · Have coached all levels from Intermediate to Varsity
- · Organized team entries and managed athletes workouts and schedules

Bubba Gump's Shrimp Co. - Host

June 2015 - August 2015

- · Cleaned tables and organized seating for customers
- · Greeted customers and cared to their needs
- · Coordinated tasks with other hosts and servers to quickly set tables and accommodate guests

The Spot - Cook

June 2016 - August 2016

- Worked with 1-2 other cooks to make and serve hot dishes in a quick manner
- Managed the cashier register



Projects

Playto Fall 2017

- Unity, C#, Game Design
- A 2D puzzle platformer game where the player plays as a piece of playdoh and must solve puzzles to progress through levels and find new purpose after his kid no longer plays with him.
- Worked with a team of five (including myself) animation and computer science students
- · Game was recognized for 'Best Technical Achievement' and 'Best Overall Game' in the class

Turretz March 2018

- Augmented Reality, Unity, C#, Game Design
- A tower defense game made in augmented reality for the 2018 Honolulu Hackathon. The game will map out the
 player's environment and allow him or her to freely place turrets wherever they please to offer a fresh experience
 every time it is played. Also includes networking to allow other users to play cooperatively from mobile devices.
- · Worked with a team to develop this game
- · Was the primary programmer for game logic, mechanics, and spatial mapping
- · Game was awarded the first place prize for 'Best Gaming/Entertainment App' of \$1000

RUNba Rush January 2018

- Unity, C#, Game Design
- A short indie puzzle game made for Global Game Jam 2018 where the player must simultaneously control multiple RUNbas (Roombas) to clean up hazards around the house before the toddler eats them.
- · Worked with others to develop this game
- · Was the primary programmer for this project
- · Game was voted as the most 'Dramatically Diverse' out of all the games in Honolulu

Super Circle Joe Spring 2017

- Java, Game Design
- A 2D bullet hell style arcade shooter where the player plays as a circle and must defeat endless waves of enemy squares and bosses. The player must change the color of their weapon to efficiently defeat enemies.
- · This was a solo project I created in my free time

Education

University of Hawaii at Manoa

August 2015 – present

- Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science
- · Coursework in programming with C, Java, JavaScript, and HTML
- Took a game design course that was taught with Unity and C#
- · Conduct self-directed research as part of the Laboratory for Advanced Visualization and Applications (LAVA)
- · Have taken additional math, speech, and writing classes
- Expected Graduation is Spring/Fall 2019



Mid-Pacific Institute

- GPA: 4.16 /4.00
- Took a course in robotics with Vex Robotics
- Graduated with International Baccalaureate and Advanced Placement classes

Technical Skills

 $\textbf{C}, \textbf{C\#}, \textbf{Java}, \textbf{JavaScript}, \textbf{HTML}, \textbf{LaTeX}, \textbf{Terminal}, \textbf{Unix}, \textbf{Unity} \ (\textbf{Both } 2\textbf{D} \ \textbf{and} \ 3\textbf{D}), \textbf{XSplit}, \textbf{Augmented \& Virtual Reality}$

Microsoft Office, Google Suite, Pages, Eclipse

Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, OBS